Guide to the Elias Fulp Papers, 1872-1908 and undated RL.00425
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Elias Fulp papers
1858-1908 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Fulp, Elias
RL.00425
889
2 Linear Feet
Elias Fulp was a physician from Walnut Cove, North Carolina. Postmaster of Fulp, North Carolina. The collection consists of correspondence and other papers pertaining to Fulp's role as trustee for Sidney H. Reid, who had just gone into bankruptcy. There are also several account books with accounts of a physician's practice.
3 individual volumes (Volumes 1-3); 1 box holding 5 additional volumes (Volumes 4-8) and 3 folders.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, collection may contain materials to which the Acknowledgment of Legal Responsibilities and Privacy Rights form applies. Patrons must sign this form before using this collection.
Also, all or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. Consequently, there may be a 24-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Elias Fulp Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1956.
Collection Overview
Collection consists of correspondence and other papers pertaining to Fulp's role as trustee for Sidney H. Reid, who had just gone into bankruptcy. There are also several account books with accounts of a physician's practice.
Arrangement
Collection's Volumes 1-3 are individually boxed and barcoded. Volumes 4-8 are all held in Box 1. All folders are also held in Box 1.
Bankruptcy -- North Carolina; Physicians -- North Carolina -- History; Medicine -- Practice -- Accounting; Account books; Fulp, Elias
- Correspondence, 1869-1902 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Personal and professional correspondence related to life and professional practice of Dr. Fulp.
- Account Book, 1870-1876 (Box 1, Volume 5)
  Ledger for practice of Dr. Fulp, includes names of individuals, dates of visits and calls, and payment received or owed.
- Account Book, 1882-1884 (Box 1, Volume 6)
- Account Book, 1884-1885 (Box 1, Volume 7)
- Cash and Expense Book, 1884-1888 (Volume 2)
  Ledger for practice of Dr. Fulp with names of debtors and creditors with dates of debits and credits.
- Account Book, 1886-1894 (Box 1, Volume 8)
- Day Book, 1887-1889 (Volume 3)
- Account Book, 1888-1891 (Box 1, Volume 4)
- Daily Account of Practice, 1900-1908 (Volume 1)
- Bankruptcy Proceedings, 1903-1906 (Box 1)
  Correspondence, receipts, payment stubs, and legal documents relating to Dr. Fulp's role as trustee for S.H. Reid during bankruptcy proceedings for the latter's general store.
- Bankruptcy Proceedings, 1905 (Oversize-folder 1)
  Notice of trustee sale for assets of S.H. Reid and fragment of ledger.
- Ledger Fragment, undated (Box 1)
  Fragment of a ledger containing names but no account information